

Residence Mariem, Building N°2, Apt N°7, El Mourouj 3, 2074, Ben Arous

🛘 (+216) 22-230-310 | 🗷 smida.haroun@gmail.com | 🖸 smidaharoun | 🖹 haroun-smida | 🛅 harounsmida

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

Determined, passionate, hard working individual with unyielding self motivation. 2+ years of Android and 1+ year of iOS programming experience combined with a passion for mobile development and the industry. Know for good teamwork and leadership skills. Tenacious problem-solver with a strong work ethic. Willing to relocate anywhere

Work Experience _____

Orange Tunis, Tunisia

Aug. 2016 - PRESENT ANDROID/IOS DEVELOPER

- · Created fully functional applications for Android and iOS & wrote clean, clear, efficient, well-tested, and maintainable code.
- Contribute and participate in new feature/product specifications.
- · Supervised trainees in their graduation projects.
- Provided training sessions in various fields and languages (Swift, Kotlin, Git...).

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, Swift, Objective-C, Git, Scrum, Tuleap, Gitlab

Orange Tunis Tunisia

INTERN - GRADUATION PROJECT Feb. 2016 - Jul. 2016

- · Developed universal iOS application (iPhone/iPad) which citizens get instant informations and statistics about their municipalities
- Developed a back-end (Laravel)

Technologies: Objective-C, Java, Git, Laravel, Scrum, ActiveColab, Gitlab

Ciblo.net Tunis, Tunisia

INTERN Feb. 2016 - Mar. 2016

• E-COM: Android/Backend e-commerce application based on CMS (prestashop) that allows user to interact with site contents from the android application with the ability to manage it from the backend

Technologies: Android, Java, Prestashop, PHP, REST-API, Git

Education4Sight Tunis, Tunisia

Jun. 2015 - Jul. 2015

• EDLIGO - Developed an android application for managing teachers lessons and notes.

Technologies: Android, Java, PHP, REST-API, Git

Certificats & Awards

CERTIFICATS

2016 TOEIC, Total Score: 940/1000 Tunis, Tunisia

AWARDS

2013 1st place, ENSIT Startup weekend Tunis, Tunisia

Presentation & Training Sessions.

Dependency Injection with Dagger 2

Tunis, Tunisia

ORANGE DEVELOPER CENTER

Oct. 2017

• An overview of Denpency Injection with some application in Android.

• Introduction to Swift syntax, basics and developing iOS application with it.

Inroduction to iOS development with Swift

Tunis, Tunisia

ORANGE DEVELOPER CENTER

Sep. 2017

HAROUN SMIDA · RÉSUMÉ NOVEMBER 25, 2017

Aug. 2017

Orange Developer Center

• Introduction to Android development fondamental and basics..

Portfolio_

Aéroport Tunisie - Android / iOS

Tunis, Tunisia

 Orange
 Jul. 2017 - Oct 2017

- The official application of OACA (Civil Aviation and Airports Authority).
- Provides real-time information of 7 airports (flight status and updates, available services...).

Technologies: Google API, Facebook API, Fabric, Firebase, Volley.

Marsad - Android / iOS Tunis, Tunisia

ORANGE Aug. 2016 - Oct 2016

· application aims to monitor municipal activity through access to information, and to present it in a clear and updated manner..

Technologies: Objective-C, Laravel, Google API

Artisans d'Art - iOS Tunis, Tunisia

Orange Nov. 2016 - Mar. 2017

· A digital platform for the promotion of trade and artisan products of the Tunisian soil

Technologies: Objective-C, Facebook API, Google API, Firebase, AFNetworking

Concouret - Android Tunis, Tunisia

Personal Nov. 2016

· Application for the lastest job offers in Tunisia

Technologies: Dagger2, Retrofit, Firebase

Other projects Tunis, Tunisia

Orange - Freelance - Personal Aug. 2016 - Oct 2017

- OBD Android/iOS
- Mina7 iOS
- · Wiki for Overwattch Android
- Tunisia Zip Code Android

Program Committees

2017 **Organizer & Coach**, Orange Summer Challenge

Tunis, Tunisia

2012 **Organizer**, Netlinks Day

Tunis, Tunisia

Education

ENSIT(High National School of Engineering of Tunis)

Tunis, Tunisia

ENGINEER'S DEGREE

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

· Speciality: Applied mathematics and modelling

FST(Faculty of Sciences of Tunis)

Tunis, Tunisia

PREPARATORY SCHOOL

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2013

• Speciality: Maths & Physics

References & Links_

Google Play

- Orange Tunisie
- WAPPSTER (Personal)

App Store

• Orange Tunisie